Preliminary Guide to the Will Inman Papers, 1910-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Will Inman papers 1910-2009
Inman, Will, 1923-
69.5 linear feet Extent: 42,754 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00614
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Portions of the collection are restricted. Researchers desiring access should consult with the Reference Archivist on duty.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Collection was purchased from Will Inman in 1998-1999 and received as a gift in 2001-2003 and in 2009.
Biographical Note
1923, May 4 Born, Wilmington, North Carolina
1943 Graduated from Duke University
1964-1971 Editor and publisher of Kauri, a poetry newsletter,
1967 Artist in residence, American University, Washington DC
1969 Married Barbara Ann Sherman
1969-1973 Member of the English faculty, Montgomery College, Rockville, MD.
1973 Divorced Legally Changed name from William A. McGirt, Jr. to Will Inman. Moved to Tucson, Arizona
Will Inman was a poet, essayist, editor, and publisher. He was born William Archibald McGirt, Jr. in Wilmington, North Carolina where his father, William A. McGirt, was in the insurance and real estate business and his mother, Delia E. McGirt (maiden name Inman), was a registered nurse. He attended Duke University, graduating with an A.B in 1943. After college, Inman worked as a union organizer for tobacco workers in North Carolina before moving to New York City in the late 1950s. He served as the Vice-president of Free University of New York in the mid 1960s. He has worked as an editor and publisher of various literary journals and has had his work published in numerous anthologies and literary journals as well as in individual volumes. His weekly column, Conchsound in the Hills, was published in the Franklin, PA News-Herald in the 1960s. In addition to writing poetry, fiction, plays, and essays, Inman was also a prolific correspondent and diarist. He was active in numerous causes, including the War in Vietnam, the Civil Rights movement, gay rights, and various environmental issues. In 1956, he was questioned by the House Un-American Activities Committee as to his relationship with the Communist Party. His activism continued into the 1990s; he led writing workshops in an Arizona State Prison, as well as teaching writing to the homeless in transition.
Collection Overview
The correspondence, diaries, manuscripts, clippings, and printed material in the Will Inman Papers span from 1939-1999, and serve to document the life and literary career of the poet, essayist, editor, educator, and publisher.
Inman was a prolific corespondent and maintained regular correspondent relationships with his friends and family, as well as with his readers and other editors and authors. He also regularly wrote to political and social figures during the 1960s. These letters to public and political figures express admiration and voice concerns about political events and social conditions. Inman protested in favor of civil rights, ending the war in Vietnam, and various environmental causes, and his letters reflect his thoughts and opinions on these subjects. Inman was also in regular contact with the editors and publishers of various literary magazines and the letters to these individuals document his efforts to publish his work. The collection holds many of Inman's out going correspondence as he regularly kept copies of his own letters.
Inman's copious diaries provide almost daily detail of his life from 1950-1994. In his diaries Inman recorded daily events, poetic inspirations, and his responses to world events. The diaries also include information about the poetry he is working on and several include typescripts of completed poems.
Inman also kept detailed records concerning his completed writings. He kept typescript copies of his poems and other writings, ordering them chronologically into notebooks, and recording publication information onto the typescripts. In organizing this collection, Inman's notebooks were discarded, but the typescripts maintain the order they held while bound in the notebooks, and serve to provide a chronological overview of Inman's published and unpublished writings.
This collection also contains copies of several of the anthologies and literary magazines where Inman published his work and several of the poetic monographs that Inman authored.
Inman regularly published his early work in newspapers in North Carolina. The collection contains clippings of these early published works as well as clippings of Inman's mid 1960's newspaper column "Conchsounds in the Hills."
There are also photographs of the McGirt family from ca. 1910, chiefly mounted in albums, as well as Inman's baby book from 1923. (16 accessions from 1998 and 1999) (35,475 items, 59 linear feet; dated 1910-1999)
The addition (accession #2001-0195) (1676 items, 2.7 linear feet; dated 1940-2001, bulk 1976-2001) comprises mainly personal correspondence to and from Inman and Jimmy Santiago Baca, 1971-1995, including typescript poetry. It also includes typescript poetry by Inman as Bill McGirt, 1940-1956; other poetry by Inman; professional correspondence; and a journal kept by Inman, 2000-2001.
The addition (accession #2002-0143) (2250 items, 3.60 linear feet; dated 1982-2001) consists primarily of incoming and outgoing personal correspondence. Topics include Inman's poems, publication work, and his political activites. There is also poetry and prose by Inman and others, and 20 black-and-white and 148 color photographs.
The addition (accession# 2003-0124 and 2003-0181)(2775 items, 3.6 linear feet; dated 1957-2003, bulk 1970-1989) contains published and unpublished typescript poetry written by Will Inman. Also includes literary newsletters, periodicals and brochures; a notebook containing poetry, biographical information and professional correspondence; and a paperweight.
Addition (2009-0263) (500 items, 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1976-2009) includes correspondence, poetry by Inman and others, press releases and reviews, official documents (such as his birth certificate, insurance information, and medical documents), and materials from Inman's death and funeral.
Subject Headings
Baca, Jimmy Santiago, 1952-; Inman, Will, 1923-; Inman, Will, 1923-. Manuscripts; McGirt, William Archibald, 1923-; Duke University -- Students; Editors -- United States; American literature -- 20th century -- Periodicals; Authors, American -- 20th century; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Diaries; Authors, American -- Southern States; Authors, American -- Southern States -- Correspondence; Authors, American -- Southern States -- Political and social views; College students -- North Carolina -- Correspondence; Communism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Diaries -- American authors; Erotic poetry, American; Free University of New York; Homosexuality -- Literary collections; Homosexuality -- Poetry; Indians of North America -- Poetry; Poets, American -- 20th century; Poets, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence; Poets, American -- 20th century -- Diaries; Political activists -- United States -- Correspondence; Political poetry, American -- 20th century; Prisoners -- Correspondence; Protest poetry, American; Tucson (Ariz.) -- Social life and customs; Tucson (Ariz.) -- Description and travel; Wilmington (N.C.) -- Description and travel; Wilmington (N.C.) -- Social life and customs; Notebooks; Diaries; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs
Contents of Collection
- Accession (1998-0338)
  Correspondence with various individuals, organizations, and literary magazines, arranged in alphabetical order. Some correspondence is foldered by subject and incorporated into the alphabetical arrangement. Also included with this accession are miscellaneous published and unpublished poetry and essays, diaries, and miscellaneous clippings and notes.
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    The correspondence includes the letters Inman received from his parents, Delia E. and William A. McGirt, while a student at Duke University from 1940-1943.The series maintains Inman's original folder titles and alphabetical arrangement.
    - Angry Arts, [St. Patrick's Day Church Protest] (Box 1)
    - Araay, Hailu (Box 1)
    - Artists of Conscience (Box 1)
    - Ashley, George (Box 1)
    - Bailey, Mary (Box 1)
    - Baird, Martha - Society for Aesthetic Realism (Box 1)
    - Baldwin, James (Box 1)
    - Bassil, Robert - Michigan Voices (Box 1)
    - Benes, Barton Lidice (Box 1)
    - Blair, Ed (Box 1)
    - Blake, Tom (Box 1)
    - Bleakley, Harriet (Box 1)
    - Blessed Damned (Box 1)
    - Berke, Joe (Box 1)
    - Bonitz, Fred (Box 1)
    - Brandt, Barbara (Box 1)
    - Boyd, Sue Abbott (Box 1)
    - Breakthru Magazine (Box 1)
    - Brown, Norman O. (Box 1)
    - Chase, Rod (Box 1)
    - Chimney Rock (Box 1)
    - Communist Party (Box 1)
    - "Conchsound in the Hills" - [Newspaper Column] (Box 1)
    - Conscientious Objector Letters (Box 1)
    - Coordinating Council for Literary Magazines (Box 1)
    - COSMEP - Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers (Box 1)
    - Cousins, Norman (Box 1)
    - Crooks Family (Box 1)
    - Day, Ashely T. (Box 1)
    - McGirt, Delia Ellen (Inman), 1939-1942, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - McGirt, William A., Sr., 1940-1943, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - McGirt, William A., Sr., 1940-1943, (5 folders) (Box 2)
    - McGirt, William A., Sr. and McGirt, Delia Ellen, 1946-1948 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Acquaintances, 1959-1970 (Box 2)
    - Whishnart, Charleen - Charlotte Observer/Red Clay Reader (Box 2)
    - Wilkinson, Bethell (Box 2)
    - Williamson, Eula - Raleigh News and Observer (Box 2)
  - Writings/Journals
    The writings include Inman's published poetry and essays for his newspaper column "Conchsound in the Hills." The journals include one diary with miscellaneous poetry from the 1960sand one diary from 1986.
    - " Conchsound in the Hills"- Poetry and Essays, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Journal / Miscellaneous Poetry 1960s, (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - Journal 1986 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Clippings and Notes, (6 folders) (Box 2)
- Accessions (1998-0346) and (1998-0367)
  These two accessions include copies of the books and literary journals featuring Inman's work; published and unpublished writings (chronological order); diaries form 1950-1994;and correspondence with various individuals and organizations (alphabetical order).
  - Diaries (Box 1)
    - 1950, May4. - 1978, Apr. 13, (16 folders) (Box 1)
  - Diaries (Box 2)
    - 1978, Apr. 14- 1994, Dec. 30, (14 folders) (Box 2)
  - Writings (Box 3)
    - Published Poems 1940s-1950s (Box 3)
    - 1940-1947 (Box 3)
    - 1948-1952 (Box 3)
    - 1951 (Box 3)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 3)
    - 1955 (Box 3)
    - 1956-1958 (Box 3)
    - 1958-1960 (Box 3)
    - 1959 (Box 3)
    - 1959-1963 (Box 3)
    - 1960 (Box 3)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 3)
    - 1963 (Box 3)
    - 1964 (Box 3)
    - 1967 (Box 3)
    - 1968, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - 1970-1974 (Box 3)
    - 1975 (Box 3)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
    - 1976 (Box 3)
    - 1977, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 1978, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 4)
    - 1980, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - 1981, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - 1982, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - 1983 (Box 4)
    - 1984 (Box 4)
    - 1985 - Stretchings: Selected Poems, 1985 (Box 4)
    - 1985 (Box 4)
    - 1987, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Writings 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - 1988, (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - 1989, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Eller, James (Box 6)
    - EPOS - Evelyn Thorne, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Evans, Richard (Box 6)
    - Evans, William McKee (Box 6)
    - Eventorium (Box 6)
    - Faber, Robert, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Falleder, Arnold (Box 6)
    - Faulkner, Stanley (Box 6)
    - Faust, Seymour (Box 6)
    - FBI - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Box 6)
    - Feldman, Eugene (Box 6)
    - Ferlinghetti, L. ( City Lights) (Box 6)
    - Fiddlehead - Fred Cogswell (Box 6)
    - Flowers, Shirley, (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - Flynn, Grace, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Foster, Musa (Box 6)
    - Fowler, Gene (Box 6)
    - Fowler, John (Box 6)
    - Fox, Hugh (Box 6)
    - Fox, Leonard (Leonid) (Box 6)
    - Frances, Thomas (Box 6)
    - Frantz, Laurent and Marge (Box 6)
    - Freelance (Box 6)
    - Free University - NY, (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - French, Elizabeth (Box 6)
    - French, Elizabeth, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - French, Warren (Box 7)
    - Friends World Institute (Box 7)
    - Fromm, Erich, Dr. (Box 7)
    - Gauthier, Carol Anne (Box 7)
    - Genesis (theatre) (Box 7)
    - Georeakas, Dan (Box 7)
    - Gerstman, Eric (Box 7)
    - Giles, Dolores (Box 7)
    - Glassman, Marlene (Box 7)
    - Glaze, Andrew (Box 7)
    - Glenn, Jerome Clayton (Box 7)
    - Golden, Harry (Carolina Israelite) (Box 7)
    - Goliards, Paul and Mariah (Box 7)
    - Gottesman, Marie (Box 7)
    - Gove, James ( Showcase) (Box 7)
    - Greigs, N.A. and Beth (Box 7)
    - Greiger, William (Bill) (Box 7)
    - Grinberg, Miguel ( Argentina) (Box 7)
    - Harpers (Box 7)
    - Harrington, Donald Szantho (Box 7)
    - Harriot, Samuel (Box 7)
    - Harris, Barry ( Theiner Well) (Box 7)
    - Hayden, James L. and Barbara Lee (Box 7)
    - Head, Robert (NOLA) (Box 7)
    - Heifferon, B. (Box 7)
    - Hirschhorn, Paul (Box 7)
    - Hoag, Bonnie Elizabeth (Box 7)
    - Hoffman, Jill (Steinberg) (Box 7)
    - Hodges, Walter (Box 7)
    - Holcomb, Della and Lester (Box 7)
    - Holland, Barbara (Box 7)
    - Homik (Box 7)
    - Honey in Hot Blood (Box 7)
    - Hopkins, Velma (Box 7)
    - Horn, Jon (Box 7)
    - Hubbard, Grigsby (Box 7)
    - Hughes, Tom (Box 7)
    - I am the Snake Handler: Lament and Psalm (Box 7)
    - I Ching (Box 7)
    - Inman, Samuel Guy (Box 7)
    - Janes, Kelly (Box 7)
    - Jawarski, Richard (Box 7)
    - Jerome, Sister Gail (Box 7)
    - Jervay, T.C. ( Wilmington Journal) (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Anne Rhodes (Box 7)
    - Johnson Lyndon B. (Box 7)
    - Jones, Leroi (Box 7)
    - Jones, Mrs. Prescott ( Aunt Nell Inman) (Box 7)
    - Jones, Thomas L. (Box 7)
    - Joseph, Clifford (Box 7)
    - Joshi, Ratanlal (Box 7)
    - Kauri (Box 7)
    - Kempton, Karl and Sylvia (Box 7)
    - Katz, Menke - Bitter Root (Box 7)
    - Kennedy, Laura (Box 7)
  - Published Materials - Books and Literary Journals (Box 8)
    - Vincent: The Mad Brother of Theo (Box 8)
    - New North Carolina Poetry: The Eighties (Box 8)
    - The Unitarian Universalist Poets (Box 8)
    - Images from the High Plains (Box 8)
    - Lament and Psalm (Box 8)
    - Of Poetry and Power: Poems Occasioned by the Presidency and by the Death of John F. Kennedy (Box 8)
    - Mad Windows (Box 8)
    - Gay Sunshine Journal: Gay Fiction Anthology (Box 8)
    - TOPO (Box 8)
    - Samisdat (Box 8)
    - Transports (Box 8)
    - Songs for Our Time (Box 8)
    - Poet: An International Monthly (Box 8)
    - Brother Word (Box 8)
    - Selected Poems: Will Inman and Charles Taylor (Box 8)
    - The Friendly World (Box 8)
    - REAL: Re Arts and Letters (Box 8)
    - Cross-Fertilization (Box 8)
    - South and West: An International Literary Quarterly (Box 8)
    - Uroboros (Box 8)
    - Minotaur 7 (Box 8)
    - Southwest: A Contemporary Anthology (Box 8)
    - Ironwood 19 (Box 8)
    - Pembroke Magazine (Box 8)
    - NYQ: The New York Quarterly (1972) (Box 8)
    - NYQ: The New York Quarterly (1975) (Box 8)
    - A River of Laughter (Box 8)
    - Gay and Lesbian Poetry in Our Time (Box 8)
    - Passages (Box 8)
    - We Sing Our Struggle (Box 8)
    - A Geography of Poets (Box 8)
    - In a Time of Revolution (Box 8)
    - The East Side Scene: American Poetry, 1960-1965 (Box 8)
    - Honey in Hot Blood (Box 8)
    - Black Men, White Men: A Gay Anthology (Box 8)
    - A Still Wind (Box 8)
    - Ohzone (Box 8)
    - Thirteen (Box 8)
    - Image (Box 8)
    - Cafe Solo (Box 8)
    - (Box 8)
    - I Am the Snake Handler (Box 8)
    - Fennel Stalk (Box 8)
    - Spectacular Diseases 8: Sexuality and the Argument of Art (Box 8)
    - The Windless Orchard (Box 8)
    - Scree (Box 8)
    - Swords of Darkness (Box 8)
    - Bitterroot (Box 8)
- Accession (1998-0371)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Ailey, Alvin (Box 1)
    - Akivah (Box 1)
    - Allen, Robert and Pam (Box 1)
    - Allerdice, John (Box 1)
    - Allyn, George (Box 1)
    - AMERIKA (cases in point) (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Sidney (Box 1)
    - Anthony, Philip (Box 1)
    - Approach (Box 1)
    - Archer, Norman (Box 1)
    - Arnoni, M. (Box 1)
    - Avital, Samuel (Box 1)
    - Barrett, Alice (Box 1)
    - Barry, Donald (Box 1)
    - Barth, John (Box 1)
    - Berge, Carol (Box 1)
    - Berkman, Jack and Eleanor (Box 1)
    - Berry's - Writer's Forum (Box 1)
    - Bertois, Michele (Box 1)
    - Bethell-Wilkson (Box 1)
    - Bibbs, Hart Leroi (Box 1)
    - Black Mask (Box 1)
    - Bloom, Gene (Box 1)
    - Brennan, Peg (Box 1)
    - Brill, Father Earl (Box 1)
    - Brooks, Jim David (Box 1)
    - Broome, Harry Travis (Box 1)
    - Brown, Jacqueline (Box 1)
    - Brown University (Box 1)
    - Brown, Michael (Box 1)
    - Burns, Jerry (Box 1)
    - Business, Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Callahan, Jim (Box 1)
    - Cebulski, Paul (Box 1)
    - Chodes, John (Box 1)
    - Christie, Elaine (Box 1)
    - Cintron, Wilfredo (Box 1)
    - Clarke, Michael and Frederica (Box 1)
    - Cohen, Joseph (Box 1)
    - Conchsound in the Hills (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - Cooper, P. (Box 1)
    - Corbitt, W.Z. (Box 1)
    - Cornish, Sam (Box 1)
    - Cosmos ( clippings) (Box 1)
    - Couch, Philip (Box 1)
    - Cox, Harvey A. (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Crews, Judson (Box 1)
    - Coelho, Art (Box 1)
    - Currier, Raymond (Box 1)
    - Dane, Barbara (Box 1)
    - D.C. Acquaintances (Box 1)
    - DeBaggio, Thomas and Joyce (Box 1)
    - Dentists (Box 1)
    - Dorn, Alfred (Box 1)
    - Dubois. Dr. WEB (Box 1)
    - Duke University (Box 1)
    - Duncan, Helen Zoe ( Wheaton College) (Box 1)
    - Edinburgh, Lee (Box 1)
    - Editors, Small Magazines (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - Kennedy, Sen. Robert (Box 2)
    - Kent, Art (Box 2)
    - Kriby, Rev. Roderick (Box 2)
    - Kitson, Worth (Box 2)
    - Kiviat, Erik (Box 2)
    - Kurson, Rissa (Box 2)
    - Kramer, Aaron (Box 2)
    - Krawchek, Karen and Bob (Box 2)
    - Lafferty, Michael (Box 2)
    - Laks, Rhoda (Box 2)
    - Landlords, leases, etc. (Box 2)
    - Larkins, William (Box 2)
    - Larson, Carl (Box 2)
    - Lawrence, Gale (Box 2)
    - Len, Gladys (Box 2)
    - Leal, Father John A. (Box 2)
    - Leber, Eric and Jennifer, Lorn and Jeremy (Box 2)
    - Legman, G. (Box 2)
    - Le Monde (Box 2)
    - Leslie, Joe (Box 2)
    - Levy, Bill and Rachel (Box 2)
    - Lhaman, Judy (Box 2)
    - Little, Bill and Holly (Box 2)
    - Love, Louise - Mrs. T.D. Love (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Luce (Box 2)
    - Lynx - Margaret Lee Johnson (Box 2)
    - McAlister, Mr. Lacy (Box 2)
    - McClammy, Margaret (Box 2)
    - McDowell, David (Box 2)
    - McGirt, Archibald - Family History (Box 2)
    - McGirt, Ellen Inman (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - McGirt Family (7 folders) (Box 2)
    - McGirt, W.A., Sr. - Business (Box 2)
    - McGirt, W.A., Sr. (1 folder) (Box 2)
    - McGirt, W.A., Sr., and Delia Inman (7 folders) (Box 3)
    - McGrath, Wm. (6 folders) (Box 3)
    - McGovern, Sen. George (Box 3)
    - McLaren, Ken (Box 3)
    - Major, Clarence (Box 3)
    - Manana, Herbert (Box 3)
    - Marco, Anton (Tony) (Box 3)
    - Marty, Martin E. (Box 3)
    - Martin, Sarah (Box 3)
    - Martin, Neal (Box 3)
    - Mason, Lenise (Box 3)
    - May, James Boyce (Box 3)
    - Mazurova, Alexandra (Box 3)
    - Melegrito, Elvira and Jonathon (Box 3)
    - Melvilles (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Melvilles (1 folder) (Box 4)
    - Mielke, Thelma (Box 4)
    - Mills, Barriss (Box 4)
    - Mintz, Ellen (see also McGirt, Ellen Inman) (Box 4)
    - Montegomery, George (Box 4)
    - Moraff, Barbara (Box 4)
    - Morgan, John, USMC (6 folders) (Box 4)
    - Mornin (Box 4)
    - Morris, Richard (Box 4)
    - Motive (Box 4)
    - Montgomery College - Students (Box 4)
    - Montgomery College (Box 4)
    - Mugge, Robert (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Murphy, Frank (Box 4)
    - Mutiny (Box 4)
    - National Guardian (Box 4)
    - NYU Library (Box 4)
    - News and Observer, Raleigh (Box 4)
    - Nolan, David (Box 4)
    - Norman, Ron (Box 4)
    - North Carolina Symphony (Box 4)
- Accessions (1998-0395) and (1998-0404)
  Minimally processed.
  - Correspondence, 1950s-1980s (Box 1)
    Correspondence in alphabetical order by correspondent's last name, M through Y. Some folder titles pertain to subjects, journals and poem titles, or classes Inman taught. This portion of the collection chiefly covers the early 1950s through the late 1980s. In many cases, Inman has included copies of his responses to the correspondence received.
    - McGirt, Harry (Box 1)
    - Notables (Box 1)
    - O'Brien, Jane (Box 1)
    - Of Poetry and Power (Box 1)
    - Officials (Box 1)
    - One Hundred and Eight Events (Box 1)
    - One Hundred and Eight Prayers for J. Edgar (Box 1)
    - One Hundred and Eight Verges Unto Now (Box 1)
    - Overmeyer, Barbara (Box 1)
    - Overton, Marcia (Box 1)
    - Owen, Guy (Box 1)
    - Owens, David (Box 1)
    - Paredes, Juan (Box 1)
    - PARADOX reading (Box 1)
    - Parrish, Juanita (Box 1)
    - Pavlovits, A. (Box 1)
    - Payne, John (Box 1)
    - Poetry Subscriptions (Box 1)
    - Peart, Rosalind (Box 1)
    - Peress, Dr. Irving (Box 1)
    - Perkins, Michael (Box 1)
    - Perniciaro, Tony (Box 1)
    - Perry, Phil (Box 1)
    - Phillips, Milton (Box 1)
    - Pierson, Virginia (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Pike, Steve (Box 1)
    - Planz, Allen (Box 1)
    - Plummer, Paul (Box 1)
    - POET - American Issue (Box 1)
    - Poetry Submitted [Accepted] (Box 1)
    - Poetry Magazine (Box 1)
    - Poetry Society of America (Box 1)
    - Pollack, Felix (Box 1)
    - Politicians (Box 1)
    - Pride - American University Course (Box 1)
    - Progressive Party (Box 1)
    - Protests (Box 1)
    - Protest Letters (Box 1)
    - Quakers (Box 1)
    - Quasebarth, Ron (Box 1)
    - Rafalsky, Steve (Box 1)
    - Rafferty, Michael (Box 1)
    - Ragan, Sam (Box 1)
    - Ramirez, Louise (Box 1)
    - Raphael, Lennox (Box 1)
    - Rasey, David (Box 1)
    - Raskin, Marc and Barb (Box 2)
    - Rather, Linda (Box 2)
    - Ray, Stanli (Box 2)
    - Reed, Ishmael (Box 2)
    - Relatives, Irregular (Box 2)
    - Renata, Ralph (Box 2)
    - Reyes, Carlos (Box 2)
    - Reynolds, Jack (Box 2)
    - Richards, Howard (Box 2)
    - Richardson, Tom (Box 2)
    - Right Wing (Box 2)
    - Rivera, René (Box 2)
    - Roddewig, Louis (Box 2)
    - Rose, Leanna (Box 2)
    - Rosen, Jeff (Box 2)
    - Rosen, Jon (Box 2)
    - Rosen, Rose (Box 2)
    - Rosenberg, Marc (Box 2)
    - Rosenbaum, Jean (Box 2)
    - Rother, Rev. Charles (Box 2)
    - Rubb, Cliff (Box 2)
    - Ruiz, Dennis (Box 2)
    - Russell, Bertrand (Box 2)
    - Rustin, Bayard (Box 2)
    - Saint-Geraud (Box 2)
    - Salamon, Russell (Box 2)
    - Sander, Margaret (Box 2)
    - Sanders, C.R.. (Box 2)
    - Schramm, Irene (Box 2)
    - Seiffer, Sam (Box 2)
    - Sensitivity (Box 2)
    - Shapiro, Nancy Jane (Box 2)
    - Sherman, Bob (Box 2)
    - Sherry, Ruth Forbes (Box 2)
    - Sheviakava, Clara (Box 2)
    - Siegel, Alan (Box 2)
    - Sierra, Gil (Box 2)
    - Simon, Alvin (Box 2)
    - Simpson, Bessie Maude (Box 2)
    - Singer, James (Box 2)